<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://hanfluid.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://hanfluid.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-02-19T07:30:58+00:00</updated><id>https://hanfluid.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Han Liu</title><subtitle>Personal website of Han Liu, Researcher at St. Anthony Falls Laboratory, University of Minnesota. Research in Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD). </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Getting Started with CFD: A Beginner’s Perspective</title><link href="https://hanfluid.github.io/2024/01/15/getting-started-cfd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Started with CFD: A Beginner’s Perspective"/><published>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hanfluid.github.io/2024/01/15/getting-started-cfd</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hanfluid.github.io/2024/01/15/getting-started-cfd.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="what-is-cfd">What is CFD?</h2> <p>Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) is the use of numerical analysis and algorithms to solve and analyze problems involving fluid flows. With the advancement of computing power, CFD has become an indispensable tool in both academic research and industrial applications.</p> <h2 id="key-methods">Key Methods</h2> <p>There are several fundamental approaches in CFD:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Direct Numerical Simulation (DNS)</strong>: Resolves all scales of turbulence without any modeling. Extremely expensive computationally but provides the most accurate results.</li> <li><strong>Large-Eddy Simulation (LES)</strong>: Resolves large-scale turbulent structures while modeling the smaller scales. A good balance between accuracy and computational cost.</li> <li><strong>Reynolds-Averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS)</strong>: Models all turbulent scales. Most computationally affordable but less accurate for complex flows.</li> </ul> <h2 id="getting-started">Getting Started</h2> <p>If you’re new to CFD, here are some resources I recommend:</p> <ol> <li>Start with the fundamentals of fluid mechanics (e.g., Kundu &amp; Cohen’s textbook)</li> <li>Learn a programming language (Python or Fortran/C++)</li> <li>Get familiar with open-source CFD tools like OpenFOAM</li> <li>Practice with simple canonical flows (channel flow, cavity flow)</li> </ol> <p><em>This is a sample blog post. Replace with your own content!</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Han Liu</name></author><category term="CFD"/><category term="tutorial"/><category term="fluid-mechanics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A brief introduction to Computational Fluid Dynamics for those new to the field.]]></summary></entry></feed>